# Krystian Laskowski

Warsaw, Poland · krystianlaskowski1@gmail.com · 500622734 · https://klaskowski.github.io/

#### Вю

Krystian is a Full-stack Web Developer, Coding Trainer and Hobby investor. He strives to be "Multiplier", not just a maker. In his 7 years in the industry (and coding for 15 years in total), he took part in 11 projects with millions of users for customers from US (both Silicon Valley and Wall Street Banking), Germany, Netherlands, Poland and even South Africa. What drives him is an infinite passion for solving people's problems using the power of brain and software combined.

#### Technologies overlook

Main programming languages: Java, Typescript

Application types: Single page applications, Microservices

Databases: OracleDB, MySQL, MongoDB, Solr, ElasticSearch

Frameworks: Angular, React, Spring Boot, ExpressJS

EXPERIENCE

Pearson

San Jose, CA, US / remote

Aug 2019 - Present

 $Development\ Team\ Lead$ 

- Refined feature scope of Score Reports Project for Automated Language Test Engineering department.
- Broke up a Monolith, OracleDB sourced system into AWS-based microservices.
- Provided support for a team consisting of 3 people: Java Developer, QA Engineer and UX designer.
- Technologies: Java 8, Play! Framework, Angular, OracleDB, AWS.

# Software Development Academy

Warsaw, Poland Dec 2018 - Jul 2019

Coding trainer

- SDA offers Java bootcamps that last around 6 months. They are aimed at beginners, who are ready to take Junior Java Developer role at the end of the bootcamp.
- Trainers are responsible for reparing dedicated exercises and resources for students.
- Classes last 7 hours and occur on the weekend. They involve 80% practice 20% theory.
- Topics range from Java basics, Algorithms, through Unit testing, Design Patters, to Hibernate and Spring framework.

## Ergo Digital IT

Warsaw, Poland Aug 2018 - Jul 2019

Full-stack developer

- Migrated legacy systems into a cloud, microservice architecture.
- As a result, two registration and authentication systems (with distinct process) were merged under OpenIAM with Informatica warehouse as a data source.
- Technologies: Java 8, Spring Boot, Node.js, React, MongoDB, Openshift.

## Citibank Europe PLC

Warsaw, Poland

Full-stack developer & Front-end Lead

Nov 2017 - Jul 2018

- Developed real-time risk analytics tools MAPS (Multi-asset portfolio system).
- Improved user experience and efficiency by introducing relevancy scoring to a multi-purpose search tool (using Solr as a storage and query engine).
- Improved automation and generating reports (generic, multi-dimensional charts, i.e. sankey chart, drilldown, bell curve / normal distribution).
- Technology stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Solr, Angular 6, HighCharts, KDB.

#### ING Bank (via Intive)

Wroclaw, Poland Dec 2015 - Oct 2017

Frontend developer

- Developed single page application (also used via a web-view) for personal banking.
- Implemented Responsive UI's together with designers, maintaining custom components repository.

- Implemented WCAG standards into application (usability guidelines for people with disabilities).
- Technologies: Backbone.js, AngularJS, React, Angular, Polymer, Webpack, ExpressJS.

# Firmao / Belcentrale (via Firmao) Full-stack developer

Lodz, Poland / Rotterdam, Nederlands Jun 2013 - Nov 2015

- Developed Firmao CRM system features, e.g. integration with external SOAP/REST API (Google Calendar, Pingen).
- Initiated a cooperation with Belcentrale, which ended up with creating a new distributed team and kick-off of a new social lending platform CapitalCircle.nl.
- Technologies: Java 6, Scala, Play Framework, ExtJS.

### EDUCATION

Wroclaw University of Technology
MS Computer Science
2014 - 2016
Lodz University of Technology
BS Computer Science
2009 - 2013
Interests

Entrepreneurship, Stock Exchange, Psychology